The only thing more dangerous than war... is love.
The Edge of Love is a drama, history, romance film directed by John Maybury.
When the Welsh poet Dylan Thomas and his flirtatious wife Caitlin sweep into war-torn London,
the last thing they expect is to bump into Dylan's childhood sweetheart Vera.
Despite her joy at seeing Dylan after so many years, Vera is swept off her feet by a dashing officer, William Killick, and
finds herself torn between the open adoration of her new found beau and the wily charms of the exotic Welshman.
Vera Phillips, played by Keira Knightley.
Caitlin MacNamara, played by Sienna Miller.
Dylan Thomas, played by Matthew Rhys.
William Killick, played by Cillian Murphy.
Ruth Williams, played by Lisa Stansfield.
Lt Col David Talbot Rice, played by Richard Dillane.
The Edge of Love is a 2008 British biographical romantic drama film directed by John Maybury
and starring Keira Knightley, Sienna Miller, Cillian Murphy, and Matthew Rhys.
The script was written by Knightley's mother, Sharman Macdonald.
Originally titled The Best Time of Our Lives, the fictional story concerns Welsh poet Dylan Thomas (played by Rhys), his wife
Caitlin Macnamara (played by Miller) and their married friends, the Killicks (played by Knightley and Murphy).
The film premiered at the Edinburgh International Film Festival on June 18, 2008, and was
released in the UK theatres two days later to mostly unfavorable critical reviews.
The story is loosely based on real events and people,
drawing on Rebekah Gilbertson's idea and David N.
Thomas' 2000 book Dylan Thomas: A Farm, Two Mansions and a Bungalow.
He has since written further about Dylan and Vera, highlighting the
several deceits in the film that trivialised their friendship.
He has described how Dylan and Vera were related as cousins, and the extent to which their families
inter-married, farming together as neighbours on the Llansteffan peninsula in Carmarthenshire.
The tone is emotional.